Industrial Designers Society of America (IDSA) Records
Industrial Designers Society of America (IDSA) Records
1944-1977
Industrial Designers Society of America.
125.0 linear ft.
Administrative papers from several earlier organizations, including the American Society of Industrial Designers and the Industrial Designers' Institute, which merged into the Industrial Designers Society of America in 1965; bound material including minutes and scrapbook; audio-visual material including slides, films, and tapes; printed material; and memorabilia.
149073
Biographical History
The term "industrial designer" originated in the U.S. Patent Office in 1913 as a synonym for the then-current term "art in industry." In 1927 Macy's department store in New York City held a well-attended Exposition of Art in Trade, which featured "modern products," many of them from the 1925 International Exposition of Modern Decorative and Industrial Arts in Paris. Public and manufacturer demand for these new "Art Deco" styles immedately surged, and a number of design professionals (including architects, package designers and stage designers) began for the first time to focus their creative efforts on mass-produced products. These professionals adopted the title of "industrial designer."
In the ensuing decades numerous organizations of industrial designers were formed, including the American Union of Decorative Artists and Craftsmen (AUDAC, ca. 1928), the National Furniture Designers' Council (NFDC, 1933), the American Designers Institute (ADI, ca. 1937), the Society of Industrial Designers (SID, 1944), the Industrial Designers Institute (IDI, 1951), and the Industrial Design Education Association (IDEA, 1957).
In 1955, SID changed its name to the American Society of Industrial Design (ASID). In 1965, after over ten years of careful negotiations, ASID merged with IDI and IDEA to form the Industrial Designers Society of America (IDSA), thus becoming "the single voice of industrial design in the US."
In 1965 IDSA had approximately 600 members in 10 chapters across the country. Its first Chairman of the Board was John Vassos (1898-1985), the founder of ADI, and its first President was Henry Dreyfuss (1904-1972). By 2000, the organization boasted over 3,300 members and 28 chapters.
IDSA's purpose is to "advances the positive impact of design on business and society while directly benefiting members by evolving into the world's most effective design organization." It strives to improve both the field of industrial design (quality, originality, innovation) and the education and careers of its members. IDSA recognizes excellence in the field via its Catalyst Awards and IDEA (International Design Excellence Awards).
[Portions of this summary adapted from IDSA's website, http://www.idsa.org/
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Industrial Designers Society of America (IDSA) Records covers more than thirty years and comprises five series.
General files contains office files from predecessor industrial design organizations (ASID, IDI) as well as files from IDSA itself; topics include among other things advertising, annual meetings, awards, clients and products, committee activities, designs, engineering, international activities, marketing, piracy and patents, public relations, and symposiums. Also here will be found material from related organizations (for example, the American Society of Civil Engineers, U.S. Chamber of Commerce, Council of Industrial Design, Eastern Arts Association, Folding Paper Box Association, National Society of Interior Designers, Society of Plastics Industry).
Bound materials contains books of meeting minutes, a guest book, scrapbook, and hotel register.
Printed matter consists of brochures, pamphlets, and periodicals of commercial origin and also periodicals and leaflets published by IDSA.
Audio-visual material includes slides, films and tapes relating to industrial design.
In the Memorabilia series will be found logos, membership pins, award certificates, photographs and various pieces of artwork.
Arrangement of the Collection
General files and Bound materials are arranged alphabetically by title/topic. Printed material is subdivided alphabetically by type and then by title. Audiovisual material and Memorabilia are arranged alphabetically by type..
Related Material
has numerous collections relating to industrial design. For a complete list, please refer to.
Subject and Genre Headings
Industrial Design; American Society of Industrial Designers -- Archives.; Industrial Designers' Institute -- Archives.; Industrial Designers Society of America -- Archives.; Design, Industrial -- United States.; Industrial designers -- United States.; Applications.; Biographies.; Brochures.; Budgets.; Correspondence.; Minutes (administrative records); Pamphlets.; Periodicals.; Photographs.; Scrapbooks.; Slides (photographs); Industrial designers.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Inventory
- General files
  - Admissions, 1965; 1968; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Advertising, 1971 (Box 1)
  - Advisory council, 1965; 1967,; 1969,; 1971,; undated; 7 folders (Box 1)
  - American Arbitration Association (Box 1)
  - American Ceramic Society (Box 1)
  - American Council of Education (Box 1)
  - American Council of Industrial Arts Teacher Education (Box 1)
  - American Craftsman Council (Box 1)
  - American Federation of Arts (Box 1)
  - American Institute of Approval (Box 1)
  - American Institute of Architects, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - American Institute of Chemical Engineers (Box 1)
  - American Institute of Decorators, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - American Institute of Die Casting (Box 1)
  - American Institute of Graphic Arts (Box 1)
  - American Institute of Industrial Engineers (Box 1)
  - American Institute of Management (Box 1)
  - American Management Association, 1957; 1958,; undated; 5 folders (Box 1)
  - American Management Association - Questionnaire, 1947 (Box 1)
  - American Marketing Association (Box 1)
  - American Personnel and Guidance Association (Box 1)
  - American Public Relations Association (Box 1)
  - American Society of Association Executives, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - American Society of Civil Engineers (Box 1)
  - American Society of Heating, Refrigeration and Air Conditioner Engineers, 3 folders (Box 1)
  - American Society of Mechanical Engineers (Box 1)
  - American Standards Association (Box 2)
  - American Trade Associarion Executives (Box 2)
    - Annual meeting, 1945-1955; 38 folders (Box 2)
    - Annual meeting, 1955-1959; 41 folders (Box 3)
    - Annual meeting, 1959-1961; 47 folders (Box 4)
    - Annual meeting, 1961-1963; 29 folders (Box 5)
    - Annual meeting, 1963-1965; 28 folders (Box 6)
    - Annual meeting, 1965-1969; 24 folders (Box 7)
    - Annual meeting, 1969-1971; 21 folders (Box 8)
  - Applications, forms and information; 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Arbitration (Box 9)
  - Architecture (Box 9)
  - Archives, 1965 (Box 9)
  - Art Directors Club (Box 9)
  - Articles of general interest (Box 9)
  - Arts Council of America, 1965 (Box 9)
  - Associate category, 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Association Executives (Box 9)
  - Associations
    - General, 1967-1971; 7 folders (Box 9)
    - Consulting Management Engineers, 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Atomic Energy Commission (Box 9)
  - Automation, 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Awards
    - General, 1952-1965; 13 folders (Box 9)
    - Competitions, 1959-1960 (Box 9)
    - Competitions, 1961-1970; 14 folders (Box 10)
    - Design, 1951-1953; 13 folders (Box 10)
    - Design, 1953-1961; 29 folders (Box 11)
    - Design, 1962-1965; 12 folders (Box 12)
    - Entries (Box 12)
    - Fashion Academy, 2 folders (Box 13)
    - Former programs (Box 13)
    - Industry, 1959-1965; 3 folders (Box 13)
    - Junior Achievement (Box 13)
    - Kaufman International, 2 folders (Box 13)
    - Koppers Competition, 2 folders (Box 13)
    - Madawick, 1965 (Box 13)
    - Merit, 1969 (Box 13)
    - Modern plastics (Box 13)
    - Packaging Council (Box 13)
    - Photos, 1960-1964; 7 folders (Box 13)
    - Pins and medals (Box 13)
    - Scholarships (Box 13)
    - Special, 1965 (Box 13)
    - Steel program, 1963 (Box 13)
    - Student administration, 2 folders (Box 13)
    - Student competition, 1956-1958; 4 folders (Box 13)
    - Student competition, 1959-1960; 2 folders (Box 14)
    - Walter Dorwin Teague (Box 14)
    - Young Artist Project (Box 14)
  - Ballots, 1953-1965; 7 folders (Box 14)
  - Barrier Free Design, 1971 (Box 14)
  - Beautificat (Box 14)
  - Bibliographical (Box 14)
  - Bibliography, 1964-1971; 12 folders (Box 14)
  - Board of Directors
    - 1945-1953, 9 folders (Box 14)
    - 1953-1965, 45 folders (Box 15)
    - 1966-1975, 16 folders (Box 16)
  - Board of Trustees
    - 1946-1957, 21 folders (Box 16)
    - 1958-1964, 23 folders (Box 17)
  - Body politic, 1968 (Box 18)
  - Bookkeeping (Box 18)
  - Book orders (Box 18)
  - Books (reviews) (Box 18)
  - Brochures - other organizations (Box 18)
  - Business, 1953-1954 (Box 18)
  - Business ad course, 1952 (Box 18)
  - Business and Professional Woman's Club (Box 18)
  - Business methods and promotions, 1955 (Box 18)
  - Business outlook (Box 18)
  - Business practice (Box 18)
  - Business promotion questionnaire, 1952 (Box 18)
  - Bylaws, 1945-1965; 21 folders (Box 18)
  - Calendar of events, 1960-1971; 5 folders (Box 19)
  - Case histories (Box 19)
  - Certificates, Engrossing (Box 19)
  - Census, 1971 (Box 19)
  - Chamber of Commerce of the U. S. (Box 19)
  - Chapters
    - General, 1955-1970; 21 folders (Box 19)
    - Allegheny, 1947-1965; 13 folders (Box 19)
    - Atlanta, 1968-1970; 3 folders (Box 19)
    - Boston, 1965-1970 (Box 19)
    - Central New York, 1965-1970; 7 folders (Box 19)
    - Chicago, 3 folders (Box 20)
    - Detroit, 1952-1970; 11 folders (Box 20)
    - Florida (Box 20)
    - Los Angeles, 1965-1971; 8 folders (Box 20)
    - Mexico City (Box 20)
    - Miami, 1967; 3 folders (Box 20)
    - Mid-East Region, 1967; 3 folders (Box 20)
    - Mid-West Region, 1947-1970; 20 folders (Box 20)
    - Minnesota (Box 20)
    - New England (Box 20)
    - New York
      - 1952-1957, 5 folders (Box 20)
      - 1957-1970, 22 folders (Box 21)
    - North-East Region, 1967-1970; 3 folders (Box 21)
    - Ohio Valley, 1967-1970; 9 folders (Box 21)
    - Pacific Coast
      - 1952-1962, 8 folders (Box 21)
      - 1962-1965, 4 folders (Box 22)
    - Philadelphia, 2 folders (Box 22)
    - San Francisco, 1967-1971; 9 folders (Box 22)
    - Southern New England, 1960-1971; 11 folders (Box 22)
    - Southern Region, 1967-1968; 2 folders (Box 22)
    - Student
      - 1967-1971, 22 folders (Box 22)
      - undated, 12 folders (Box 23)
  - Christmas gifts, 1970 (Box 23)
  - Clients and products
    - Accordian (Box 23)
    - Aerosol containers (Box 23)
    - Air conditioners (Box 23)
    - Automobile Manufacturers' Association, 2 folders (Box 23)
    - Automotive Engineers, 3 folders (Box 23)
    - Automotive industry (Box 23)
    - Autos (Box 23)
    - Aviation (Box 23)
    - Bathroom equipment, 2 folders (Box 23)
    - Baths (Box 23)
    - Batteries (Box 23)
    - Bell Telephone Labs (Box 24)
    - Bowlene (Box 24)
    - Bundy Tubing Co. (Box 24)
    - Carpet sweeper (Box 24)
    - Cash register (Box 24)
    - Century 21 (Box 24)
    - Coffee maker (Box 24)
    - Companies - miscellaneous (Box 24)
    - Computers (Box 24)
    - Construction (Box 24)
    - Control instruments (Box 24)
    - Cooking pots (Box 24)
    - Copying machine (Box 24)
    - Corn popper (Box 24)
    - Corning Glass Works (Box 24)
    - Dictaphone (Box 24)
    - Dictating equipment (Box 24)
    - Disposal (Box 24)
    - Dishwasher (Box 24)
    - Domes (Box 24)
    - Electric blanket controls (Box 24)
    - Electronics (Box 24)
    - Farm machinery (Box 24)
    - Fans, 2 folders (Box 24)
    - Flashlight and hand lamps (Box 24)
    - Floor machines (Box 24)
    - Food (Box 24)
    - Freezers (Box 24)
    - Furniture (Box 24)
    - Garage (Box 24)
    - General Motors (Box 24)
    - Hearing aids (Box 24)
    - Home fashions (Box 24)
    - Honeywell (Box 24)
    - Industrial lighting (Box 24)
    - Interiors (Box 24)
    - International Harvester Company (Box 24)
    - Irons (Box 24)
    - Jaybern Press (Box 24)
    - Juicers (Box 24)
    - Kitchen appliances (Box 24)
    - Kodak (Box 24)
    - Lawn mower (Box 24)
    - Lighting (Box 24)
    - Locks (Box 24)
    - Machine design, 2 folders (Box 24)
    - Marking devices (Box 24)
    - Massage, scalp (Box 24)
    - Medical design (Box 24)
    - Metropolitan (rapid) transit (Box 24)
    - Michigan Consolidated Gas Co. (Box 24)
    - Military and government (Box 24)
    - Mixers (Box 24)
    - Mobile homes (Box 24)
    - Motors and engines (Box 24)
    - Mousetrap (Box 24)
    - Multiprint, Inc. (Box 24)
    - Northwestern National Life Insurance Co. (Box 24)
    - Oil rigs and oil drilling (Box 24)
    - Oneida Ltd. (Box 24)
    - Paint sprayer (Box 24)
    - Pens and pencils (Box 24)
    - Photographic equipment (Box 24)
    - Piano (Box 24)
    - Picture frames (Box 24)
    - Plastics Institute (Box 24)
    - Plumbing (Box 24)
    - Porcelain enamel, 2 folders (Box 24)
    - Printing (Box 24)
    - Prospective clients
      - 1957-1962, 5 folders (Box 24)
      - 1962-1971, 13 folders (Box 25)
    - Radio (Box 25)
    - Ranges (Box 25)
    - Recording equipment (Box 25)
    - Refrigeration (Box 25)
    - Reynolds Aluminum Co. (Box 25)
    - Satellites (Box 25)
    - Saws and cutting devices (Box 25)
    - Scales (Box 25)
    - Sewing machines (Box 25)
    - Sharpeners (Box 25)
    - Shavers (Box 25)
    - Slicing machine (Box 25)
    - Solar energy (Box 25)
    - Sprinklers (Box 25)
    - Steel industries (Box 25)
    - Sun lamp (Box 25)
    - Super sonic transport (Box 25)
    - Telephones, 2 folders (Box 25)
    - Televisions (Box 25)
    - Theatre design (Box 25)
    - Toaster and waffle iron (Box 25)
    - Tools (Box 25)
    - Towers (Box 25)
    - Trains (Box 25)
    - Transportation (Box 25)
    - Triennale, 1954-1964; 8 folders (Box 25)
    - Typewriters (Box 25)
    - Upholstery Leather Group, Inc. (Box 25)
    - Urban renewal (Box 25)
    - Vacuum cleaners (Box 25)
    - Varizoom cameras (Box 25)
    - Washers and dryers (Box 25)
    - Wheelchair (Box 25)
    - Wood Office Furniture Institute (Box 25)
    - Wood and wood products (Box 25)
    - World's Fair, 1964-1965; 2 folders (Box 26)
  - Cocktail parties (Box 26)
  - Color Research Institute of America (Box 26)
  - Comet Ray Letter Service, 2 folders (Box 26)
  - Commerce, Chamber of (Box 26)
  - Committees
    - General, 1955-1969; 10 folders (Box 26)
    - Activity, 1957-1962; 6 folders (Box 26)
    - Appointments, 1949-1964; 14 folders (Box 26)
    - Lists (Box 26)
    - Reports, 1950-1963; 11 folders (Box 26)
    - Specific committee proceedings
      - Admissions, 1961-1963; 2 folders (Box 26)
      - Adult education, 1960-1962; 3 folders (Box 26)
      - Annual meeting, 1953-1954 (Box 26)
      - Biographies (Box 26)
      - Book, 3 folders (Box 26)
      - Business methods and promotion, 1952-1957; 12 folders (Box 27)
      - Bylaws, 1953-1958; 5 folders (Box 27)
      - Code of practice, 1952-1953 (Box 27)
      - Combined information and sample reference system, 1962-1963; 3 folders (Box 27)
      - Competitions, 1965 (Box 27)
      - Contracts, 1952-1953; 2 folders (Box 27)
      - Corporation activities, 1953-1954 (Box 27)
      - Credentials, 1958-1959; 2 folders (Box 27)
      - Cultural activities (Box 27)
      - Design protection (Box 27)
      - Development and planning (Box 27)
      - Directory (Box 27)
      - Education
        - 1949-1968, 19 folders (Box 27)
        - 1968-1971, 15 folders (Box 28)
      - Election, 1942 (Box 28)
      - Executive, 1959-1971; 15 folders (Box 28)
      - Exhibit, 1953-1956; 8 folders (Box 28)
      - External affairs, 1952-1956; 3 folders (Box 28)
      - Fellows, 1955-1964; 7 folders (Box 28)
      - Fellowship
        - 1954-1963, 9 folders (Box 28)
        - 1964-1965, 5 folders (Box 29)
      - Film, 1952-1960; 5 folders (Box 29)
      - Finance, 1952-1969; 11 folders (Box 29)
      - Foreign affairs, 1956-1965; 8 folders (Box 29)
      - Government relations, 1958-1962; 6 folders (Box 29)
      - Graphics, 1960; 3 folders (Box 29)
      - Grievance, 1957-1959; 2 folders (Box 29)
      - Gripe, 1952-1953 (Box 29)
      - Handicapped, employment of, 1952-1959; 4 folders (Box 29)
      - Headquarters, 1953-1956; 2 folders (Box 29)
      - High school orientation study, 1964-1965 (Box 29)
      - Homestyle Center Foundation, 1956 (Box 29)
      - Human resources (Box 29)
      - Industrial and institutional relations (Box 29)
      - Industry liaison, 1958-1965; 10 folders (Box 29)
      - Inter-society affairs (Box 29)
      - Internal activities, 1958-1963; 4 folders (Box 29)
      - Internal professional services, 1965-1967; 6 folders (Box 30)
      - Licensing, 1950-1951; 3 folders (Box 30)
      - Membership, 1949-1971; 29 folders (Box 30)
      - Membership promotion, 1952-1954; 4 folders (Box 30)
      - Museum, 1952-1955; 3 folders (Box 31)
      - National admissions, 2 folders (Box 31)
      - National meeting, 1960-1961 (Box 31)
      - New business (Box 31)
      - New chapter (Box 31)
      - Nominating, 1955-1970; 17 folders (Box 31)
      - Patents, 1954-1963; 8 folders (Box 31)
      - Pensions and insurance, 1952-1964; 12 folders (Box 31)
      - Philosophy of industrial design, 2 folders (Box 31)
      - Placement (Box 31)
      - Policy-making
        - 1955 (Box 31)
        - 1956-1965 (Box 32)
      - Public affairs, 1952; 2 folders (Box 32)
      - Public relations, 1953-1960; 8 folders (Box 32)
      - Public service, 1969-1971; 3 folders (Box 32)
      - Publications, 1953-1971; 8 folders (Box 32)
      - Professional evaluation, 1963; 5 folders (Box 32)
      - Program, 1944-1953; 3 folders (Box 32)
      - Research and statistics, 1953-1955; 5 folders (Box 32)
      - Scholarship (Box 33)
      - School approval, 1961 (Box 33)
      - Slide show, 1954-1959; 11 folders (Box 33)
      - Speakers service (Box 33)
      - Standards of professional training, 1953; 3 folders (Box 33)
      - Steering (Box 33)
      - Student activities, 1954-1955 (Box 33)
      - Student membership, 1952-1960; 2 folders (Box 33)
      - Study, 1958-1959 (Box 33)
  - Communications, 1970 (Box 33)
  - Compensation report (Box 33)
  - Consolidation program (Box 33)
  - Consultant designers' register (Box 33)
  - Consumer Affairs, 1969-1971; 3 folders (Box 33)
  - Contemporary Architecture, 1947 (Box 33)
  - Contract forms, 1960-1961; 2 folders (Box 33)
  - Control Engineering Corporation (Box 33)
  - Corporation business, 1954 (Box 33)
  - Corporation papers (Box 33)
  - Correspondence
    - 1945-1949, 6 folders (Box 33)
    - 1949-1956, 21 folders (Box 34)
    - 1956-1961, 20 folders (Box 35)
    - 1961-1963, 16 folders (Box 36)
    - 1963-1971, 39 folders (Box 37)
    - undated, 40 folders (Box 38)
    - undated, 25 folders (Box 39)
    - undated, 24 folders (Box 40)
  - Council of Industrial Design (Box 40)
  - Creativity (Box 40)
  - Current ASID (Box 40)
  - Data sheets, 2 folders (Box 40)
  - Design
    - As communication (Box 40)
    - Centers, 1967-1968; 2 folders (Box 40)
    - Contracts (Box 40)
    - Council, 1964-1965; 2 folders (Box 41)
    - Definitions (Box 41)
    - Directory (Box 41)
    - Experimental (Box 41)
    - For industry (Box 41)
    - Futurism (Box 41)
    - In corporations (Box 41)
    - Integrity, 1955 (Box 41)
    - News of interest (Box 41)
    - Notes, 1965; 2 folders (Box 41)
    - Patent litigation (Box 41)
    - Protection, 1957-1968; 12 folders (Box 41)
    - Sources of inspiration (Box 41)
    - Term paper (Box 41)
  - Designers
    - General, 2 folders (Box 41)
    - Appel/Graser -- Cushing and Neville, 36 folders (Box 41)
    - Dailey, Don -- Kraus, Walter, 92 folders (Box 42)
    - Labalme Associates, Inc. -- Myers, Stowe, 58 folders (Box 43)
    - Neafie, Harry -- Stephenson, Charles F., 83 folders (Box 44)
    - Stephenson, Charles F. -- Yang/Gardner, 59 folders (Box 45)
    - Yang/Gardner, 16 folders (Box 46)
    - Young, Raymond C. -- Non ASID, 6 folders (Box 47)
  - Designs rejected
    - General -- Commercial exteriors, 22 folders (Box 47)
    - Communications -- Windows, 37 folders (Box 48)
  - Dues structure and reviews, 1963-1965; 2 folders (Box 49)
  - Eastern Arts Association (Box 49)
  - Economics (Box 49)
  - Education
    - General, 1952 -- Association, 28 folders (Box 49)
    - Association -- Business school indoctrination, 1967, 25 folders (Box 50)
    - Career briefs, 1968 -- Nominations, 38 folders (Box 51)
    - Occupational briefs, 1968 -- Schools and universities, 26 folders (Box 52)
      - General -- Auburn University, 9 folders (Box 52)
      - Bridgeport -- Western Reserve, 59 folders (Box 53)
      - Wisconsin -- Yale, 2 folders (Box 54)
    - Statistical survey -- Working file, 15 folders (Box 54)
  - Elections, 1948-1965; 13 folders (Box 54)
  - Electronics (Box 54)
  - Employee rating survey (Box 54)
  - Employee's agreement (Box 54)
  - Engineering, 3 folders (Box 54)
  - Engineering, human and value, 2 folders (Box 54)
  - Engineers' Joint Council (Box 54)
  - Executive secretary salary guide (Box 54)
  - Executives (Box 54)
  - Exhibits
    - General, 1947-1958, 12 folders (Box 54)
    - General, 1957-1971 -- "Design in America", 33 folders (Box 55)
    - "Design in America" -- Museums, 23 folders (Box 56)
      - General, 1970-1971; 6 folders (Box 56)
      - A-Z (Albright Art Gallery to West Coast Museums), 38 folders (Box 57)
  - Fact sheet, 1965; 2 folders (Box 57)
  - Federal Advisory Commission on the Arts (Box 57)
  - Final reservations, 1951-1952 (Box 57)
  - Financial
    - Accountant, 1960 -- Bills, 1961, 24 folders (Box 58)
    - Bills, 1961 -- Budgets, 1965, 16 folders (Box 59)
    - Budgets -- Statements, 1957, 58 folders (Box 60)
    - Statements, 1958 - Treasurer, 1965, 25 folders (Box 61)
    - Treasurer, 1970, 3 folders (Box 62)
  - First National City Bank of New York (Box 62)
  - Ford Foundation (Box 62)
  - Foundation, 1971 (Box 62)
  - Folding Paper Box Association, 2 folders (Box 62)
  - Free design service, 4 folders (Box 62)
  - Government, 11 folders (Box 62)
  - Graphics, 1966-1971 (Box 62)
  - Group insurance (Box 62)
  - Guidance program, Teague (Box 62)
  - HUD study, 1970 (Box 62)
  - Handbook material
    - Chapter manual -- Ethics, industry, 1969, 32 folders (Box 62)
    - Ethics, Industry, 1970 -- Student chapter manual, 29 folders (Box 63)
  - Handicapped, employment and criteria, 3 folders (Box 63)
  - History
    - General, 1969-1970; 8 folders (Box 63)
    - General -- Organization, 18 folders (Box 64)
  - House of Representatives Standing Committee (Box 64)
  - How to Use an Industrial Designer (Box 64)
  - Human engineering (Box 64)
  - Human Factors Society, 1970-1971; 2 folders (Box 64)
  - Incorporation vs. partnership of industrial design practice, 1955 (Box 64)
  - Industrial Designers Guild (Box 64)
  - Industrial Design Institute, 4 folders (Box 65)
  - Industrial Design Students' Association (Box 65)
  - Industrial marketing (Box 65)
  - Industry, 1964-1965; 5 folders (Box 65)
  - Industry liaison, 1967-1971; 6 folders (Box 65)
  - Infringements or piracy (Box 65)
  - Insurance, 1952-1970; 13 folders (Box 65)
  - Inter-society
    - General -- Affairs, 6 folders (Box 65)
    - Affairs -- Structure and procedures, 42 folders (Box 66)
  - Interim report, 1969-1971; 3 folders (Box 66)
  - Internal activities, 1965-1969; 2 folders (Box 66)
  - International
    - General, 1965-1969; 4 folders (Box 66)